Guide to the John Graves Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Other Writings, 1946-2003, undated
  - "Recollections of a Texas Bird Glimpser" - photocopy of uncorrected galleys (Of Birds and Texas), 1981-1985, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "The Reminiscence of an American Friend," second draft, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "Rice University: The Pangs of Change" - photocopy of article, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Rice University: The Pangs of Change" - Holiday issue with article, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - "Some Notes on Texas Landscapes" (introduction to Texas Landscapes) – correspondence, partial early draft, fragments, first-third drafts, corrected page proofs, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Southern Living pieces – correspondence, carbon copies of submissions, notes, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "The Spanish Myth in Literature" – The New Leader issue, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "A Special Place: The Texas Hill Country" – cassette tapes (2), undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "The Speckled Horse" - typescript fragments, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "The Speckled Horse" - carbon copy fragments, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Stanford, Geoffrey piece – corrected typescript fragments, correspondence, 1979, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Staub, Jack reminiscence – correspondence, corrected typescripts (3), 1983, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Story of Them (The Owl)" – notes, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Tenerife writings – manuscript note (in Spanish), translation, correspondence, photocopies of articles (in Spanish), note, 1955-2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "Texas as Maybe a Place" - first and second drafts, correspondence, corrected submitted typescript, 1977, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Texas Monthly Columns, 1977-1986, undated
    - "All That Litters" – corrected draft, fragments (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Big River" – corrected draft, fragments (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Building Fever" – corrected drafts (2), fragments (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Dead Oaks" – correspondence, notes, fragments, corrected first-third drafts, research, galleys (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Drinking" - corrected drafts (2), fragments (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "The Exhausted Land" - fragments (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Fencing Myself In" - fragments, notes (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "The Heat Treatment" – corrected drafts (2), fragments (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Kindred Spirits" – corrected draft and proof copies, fragments, clipping (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Lord of the Flies" – corrected drafts (2), fragments, notes (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "The Loser" – corrected drafts (2), fragment (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Poultry in Motion" – corrected typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Sacred Cows" – notes, fragments, corrected drafts (3), correspondence (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "The Snuff of Dreams" – fragments, corrected drafts (3) (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Stayin' Alive" – fragments, corrected drafts (2), galleys (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Through All Kinds of Weather" – fragments, corrected drafts (2) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Whose Woods Are These?"– fragments, corrected drafts (2) (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "The World to Wine" - corrected draft (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Texas Monthly Correspondence, 1975-1984 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Texas Monthly issues, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Texas Monthly issues, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Texas Monthly issues, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Texas Monthly Published Pieces I", 1976-1978 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
  - "Texas Monthly Published Pieces II", 1979-1985 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - 'Texas Novel Notes' – manuscript and typescript notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Texas Skies introduction – correspondence, printout drafts (2), 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - This Stubborn Soil introduction – corrected drafts (2) and fragments, notes, 1986, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Thoughts on the Occasion of a Second Viet Nam Moratorium" –correspondence, corrected typescript, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "TMT" – corrected carbon copy, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "To Voters Who Care What Happens to Somervell County" –fragment, miscellaneous pages, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Tribute to George Williams for Sallyport" – correspondence, corrected carbon copy, copies of Sallyport (2), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "The Truth of the West" – copies of The New Leader (2), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Untitled essay – miscellaneous pages, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Untitled fragment, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - "U.S. Go Home" – clipping, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - "A Valley" – corrected carbon typescripts (3), 1954 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Vaquero introduction - log, correspondence, text, notes, passages, 1992-2003 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Vaquero introduction - page proofs, 1992-2003 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Varmints project – correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - "Walker, on the Wild Side" – correspondence, printout draft, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "Who's Gonna Shoe Your Foot?" – fragments, notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - 'Y2K Piece for Dallas Morning News' – printout draft, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Speeches, 1979-1998, undated
  The third series covers speeches that Graves wrote and delivered, arranged alphabetically by the event or occasion. Like the previous two series, these files contain drafts, correspondence, published forms, notes and other materials related to their subjects.
  - Dallas Historical Society Awards for Excellence (for A.C. Greene) – correspondence, program, BOT list, manuscript of remarks, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Richard memorial service – typescript, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Knopf tribute at Harry Ransom Center – correspondence, printout of remarks, poster, publication, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "The Old Guard: Dobie, Bedichek & Webb" – correspondence, invitations, programs, notes, fragments, drafts (3) of speech, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Reid, Jan benefit dinner – corrected printout of remarks, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "Sense of Place" talk for University of Dallas – corrected typescript of remarks, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "The Southwest as the Cradle of the Writer" – The American Southwest: Cradle of Literary Art (book with text of speech), 1981 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Southwestern Writers Collection opening – drafts (4) of speech, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Texas Folklore Society / Friends of the Texas A&M University Library meeting – correspondence, notes, fragment, drafts (2), 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Texas Institute of Letters - acknowledgement of McCombs/Tinkle Award – correspondence, program, press release, speech notes, fragments and drafts (2), 1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "T.I.L. [Texas Institute of Letters] piece for A.C. [Greene]" – corrected typescript and fragment, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - "Texas Myths and Texas Writing" – notes, fragments, drafts (4), 1984 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Trinity Valley School Commencement Address – newsletter with text of speech, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Western Writers Symposium in Albany, TX – correspondence, clipping, printout of speech (not used), 1998 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1943-2006, undated; 1959-2006
  The Correspondence series contains letters that highlight Graves' writing career, with letters to and from publishers, agents, fellow writers, fans, event organizers and others. Insights into Graves' personal life and thoughts are also found in letters between Graves and longtime friends and family members. Graves kept carbon copies and later computer printout copies of many of his letters to others, so the researcher gets both sides of the letter-writing dialogue, in these folders and elsewhere in the collection where correspondence is included.
  The vast majority of the correspondence is filed alphabetically by last name, though in a handful of cases by institution name, event name, or subject. Within the folders that are labeled with a range of names the correspondence is arranged and labeled in smaller folders. Folders that have just one name written on them means the volume of letters warranted its own folder (or in some cases, more than one folder).
  The correspondence in the John Schaffner file is notable for chronicling the agent-writer relationship. Schaffner was Graves' agent until 1979, and this file, covering eighteen years, highlights their personal and professional association during that time. Writers Rick Bass, Angus Cameron, Nick Lyons and John N. Cole have considerable amounts of correspondence with Graves, as does writer and photographer Bill Wittliff, who has also been a close friend of and sometime collaborator with Graves through the years. Though less voluminous, the letters between Graves and Cormac McCarthy reveal a respect and kinship between the two men.
  Daughters Helen Graves and Sally Jackson also have a considerable amount of correspondence in this series. Fleet Lentz and Abe Rothberg each have multiple folders, making evident their important friendships with Graves. Another significant friendship documented in letters is that of Graves and Samuel Hynes, who have been close friends since their days together at Columbia University. These letters are arranged in two parts, one restricted and one not. Letters donated by Mr. Hynes himself for inclusion in the John Graves Papers are restricted from access until after the deaths of both gentlemen. There are also two other, unrelated letters placed at the end of the series that are restricted until 30 years after the death of Mr. Graves.
  - Adlai Stevenson Institute of International Affairs, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - A - Arteseros, 1976-2001, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Associated - Avila, 1980-2002 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - B - Bass, Ramona, 1991-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Bass, Rick, 1990-2005 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Battle - Bode, 1966-2002, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Bodio, Steve, 1990-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Bourbon - Brunk, 1979-2003 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Buck, Homer, 1995-2006 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Bull - Bush, 1977-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - C - Callery, 1994-2000, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cameron, Angus, 1980-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Camp - Card, 1993-2001 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Cardenas, Jeffrey (Waterlight/The Saltwater Angler), 1987-2005 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Carney - Clark, Carol Lee, 1992-2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Stephen L. (SLC Photographs/Gallery), 1995-2004 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Clark, Steve - Coifton, 1994-2004, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Cole, Henry, 1984-2004 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Cole, John N., 1979-2002 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Collins - C-unknown, 1965-2006, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Davenport - Dixon, 1976-2005, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Dobie / Paisano Project, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Dobson - Donovan, 1985-2000, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Douglas, Deborah D., 1993-2001 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Douglas, Sam - D-unknown, 1943-2002 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - E - Erickson, Eric, 1979-2001, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Erickson, John R., 1977-2006 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Etheridge - E-unknown, 1978-2006, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - F - Fondren, 1980-2003, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Foote, A. Lee, 1990-1996 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Fort Worth Day School, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Foster - Furman, 1981-2004 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - G - Graham, 1981-2006 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Graves, Helen / Princeton University, 1977-1981 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Graves, Helen, 1989-2004 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Graves, Jo - Groome, 1944-2006, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Grover, Dorys Crow (East Texas State University), 1985-2004 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1962-1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Guthrie - G-unknown, 1995-2004, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - H - Hagan, 1980-2006 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Hale, Leon, 1991-2005 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Halpern - Hannah, 1991-2002, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Hard Scrabble Book Sales, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Harkins - Harrison, Kitty, 1991-2005, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Harrison, Thomas P. III, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Hartley, Margaret L. (Southwest Review), 1965 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Hart - Hiatt, 1992-2006, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Hickey, David C., 1963, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Hightower - Hollingsed, 1981-2004, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Holt - Huston, 1992-2005 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Hynes, Samuel (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Hynes, Samuel, unrestricted, 1976-2005, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - I, 1981-1999 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - J - Jackson, Harry, 1966-1992, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Sally, Robert and family, 1988-2005, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Jaskilla - Jones, Kathryn, 1987-2004, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Stephen, 1974-2001 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - 'Journal Fragments', 1959-1965 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Juannah - J-unknown, 1972-2003 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - K - Kerr, 1979-2003 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Kilgore, Rick, 1996-2001 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Killian - Klintenick, 1979-2002 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Knopf, 1960-1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Koger - Kopp, 1976-99 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - L - Leeson, 1974-2005, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Lentz, Fleet, 1995-2004, undated (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
  - Leonard - Lipscomb, 1991-2004, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Lish, Gordon (Behavorial Research Laboratories / Educational Development Corporation), 1965-1968, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Livingston - Lyons, 1980-2004, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Lyons, Nick, 1987-2005, undated (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - M - MacLeod, 1992-2002, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Macrorie, Ken (CCCC Journal), 1961-1963 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Madigan - McCurdy, 1979-2005, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - McDonald - McVean, 1978-2002 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Meichsel - Mitchem, 1981-2006, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery, Phil, 1994-2005, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Mooney - Mussehl, 1977-2005, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - N, 1981-2002, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - O, 1978-2003, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Pacini - Palmer, 1995-1999 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Paluxy River Program, 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Parham - Pugh, 1981-2006, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - R - Rogoyska, 1969-2005, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Rothberg, Abe, 1997-2006 (Box 29, Folder 10, Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Rothberg, Lewis - Rutson, 1962-2002, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - S - Schafer, 1981-2003, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Schaffner, John, 1961-1979 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Schaffner, Val - Shaw, 1980-2006 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Shearer, Bill, Travis, Kathy, 1985-2004 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Sheffield, Dick, 1997-2000 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sheets - Southwestern, 1961-2004, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Spiegelman - Swank, 1972-2005, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Tarkington, Sallie estate, 1968-1992, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Taylor - Texas Book & Author Brunch, 1981-2004 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Texas Book Festival, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Texas Christian University (contracts and correspondence), 1960-1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Texas Christian University Sigma Tau Delta - Tynan, 1979-2003, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - U - V, 1979-2001 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - W - Watt, 1962-2003, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Weems, Eddie (UT Press / Baylor University), 1963-1996 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Weeren - Wiley, 1991-2004, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Williams, George: Distinguished Alumni Award, Rice University, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Williams - Wilson, 1991-2002, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Winckler, Suzanne, 1985-2005 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Winship - Wishcamper, 1994-1997 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Wittliff, Bill, Reid and Sally, 1971-2004, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Woo - Wynne, 1992-2003, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Y-Z, 1996-2005, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - RESTRICTED (2 letters to be opened 30 years after Graves' death) (Box 31, Folder 14)
- Institutional Activities, 1960-1998
  There are two main parts to this series: Texas Institute of Letters, and Classes and Workshops. The former sub-series deals with Graves' membership in and activities with T.I.L., including two folders of his 1971-73 presidency of the organization; while the latter sub-series contains syllabus information and notes related to two courses and one workshop taught by Graves. The files in these two sub-series are arranged chronologically. The last part in Institutional Activities is a file relating to the "John Graves Essay Contest," conducted by The University of Texas Press. Graves was the judge of the final three-place winners of the contest.
  - Texas Institute of Letters, 1961-1997; 1964-1973
    - Meetings, membership, newsletters (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Carr P. Collins & Friends of the Dallas Public Library Awards (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Executive Committee (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Periodical Prose Award contest (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Taste" symposium (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Presidency (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Classes & Workshops Taught, 1960-1981
    - English 332 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Writing course (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Fort Worth Country Day School (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - "John Graves Essay Contest", 1997-1998 (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Awards and Honors, 1961-2004; 1975-1997
  This series is arranged chronologically, and contains mainly invitations, programs and photographs related to awards and honors bestowed upon Graves. A significant portion of this series deals with the Dallas Museum of Art's "John Graves Day," celebrated in May 1995, and includes video recordings of the event as well as correspondence, clippings and programs.
  - Texas State Resolution No. 487, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Collins Award for Best Texas Work of Non-Fiction, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Dinner for Jim Bones and John Graves, Texas A&M, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - American Book Awards nomination, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Texas Christian University Honorary Doctor of Letters degree, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Distinguished Alumni, Association of Rice Alumni, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Texas Lecture and Symposium on the Humanities, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Dallas Awards for Excellence in Community Service, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Literary Lions Dinner, Friends of the Dallas Public Library, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - "Texas Images and Realities" panelist, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - John Graves Day, 1994-1997
    - Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Photographic images (106 slides & 2 negatives) (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Video recordings of event, part 1 & 2 (2 VHS & 2 DVD copies) (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Video recordings of event, part 3 & 4 (2 VHS & 2 DVD copies) (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Program & clippings (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Texts of speeches (Helen & Sally Graves) (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Book and Author Luncheon, Hood County Friends of the Library, circa 2000 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Lifetime Achievement Award, Texas Medal of Arts, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - "One Book, One Arlington", 2003 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Ninth Annual Stars of Texas Preservation Awards, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - International Award of Excellence in Conservation, Botanical Research Institute of Texas, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 21)
- Personal Materials, circa 1920-2002; 1938-1999
  Notebooks, legal papers, financial papers, photographs, journals, objects and academic records make up the majority of the materials in this series. Graves' academic career is well documented through grade reports and written recommendations, class notes from undergraduate and graduate school, and his Columbia University Master's thesis on William Faulkner. Of particular interest in this series is the notebook Graves used while traveling in Europe and his journal of a trip down the Rio Conchos, as well as many copy prints of family photographs. Objects of note include Graves' Royal Standard typewriter and the paddle and tent he used during his canoe trip down the Brazos River in 1957. Materials in this series are arranged chronologically according to sub-series.
  The "Reading Notes" journals in Box 38 may not be viewed or duplicated without the permission of John Graves or Bill Wittliff.
  - Photographs, 1920-1990
    - Originals (1), 1920-1929 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Originals (1), 1930-1939 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Originals (6), 1940-1949 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Originals (11), 1950-1959 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Originals (1), 1960-1969 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Originals (3), 1970-1979 (Box 34, Folder 6, Box 47)
    - Originals (7), 1990-1999 (Box 34, Folder 7, Box 47)
    - Copy prints (27), circa 1920-1929 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Copy prints (3), circa 1930-1939 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Copy prints (9), circa 1940-1949 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Copy prints (18), circa 1950-1959 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Copy prints (19 b/w, 5 color), circa 1960-1969 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Copy prints (61 b/w, 1 color), circa 1970-1979 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Copy prints (5 b/w, 3 color), circa 1980-1989 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Copy prints (13 b/w, 13 color), circa 1990-1999 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Copy negatives (30 strips), circa 1920-1999 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Academics, circa 1938-1948
    - Grades (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Rice Institute notes (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Columbia University notes (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Master's essay (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - 'Reading Notes' – RESTRICTED, 1946-1969
    - Notes on contents and restrictions (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - 'Reading Notes' journals in binders (2) (Box 35)
  - Legal & Financial, 1946-1976
    - Veterans Affairs (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Texas Veterans Land Program (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Somervell County property (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Equitable Savings Association (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Andrea Muro immigration (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Frances C. Graves estate (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Jackson County farm (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Home and farm insurance (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Income Tax notes (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - ID Cards, 1948-1955 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1948-1997
    - Dreams (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Europe (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Milton, various books, Spanish language, Spain (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - 'Livestock' (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - 'Jackson CountyLand Sale Negotiations' (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - 'Florida Fishing Notes' (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - 'Texas Coast Notes' (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - 'Fishing, Fly-Tying, Rod-Making, etc.' (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - 'Florida Keys Fishing Notes' (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter for Retired Marines, 1957-1999 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Research, 1960-1994
    - Mississippi trip, maps (2)– correspondence, clipping (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Audubon/conservation lectures - outlines, clipping, publications (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear power plant in Somervell County - correspondence, clippings (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Home projects - notes, diagrams, drawings, product literature (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Comanche Peak Plant - correspondence, clippings, copies of affidavits, reports and memos (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Born of the River forward – correspondence, reports, LCRA literature (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Rio Conchos trip, 1965-1967
    - Notebook (Prospectus, correspondence, notes, slide index, clippings) (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Slides (61) (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Trinity Valley School, 1973-2000
    - Children's enrollment (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Newsletter (with reprinted 1960 Mission Statement written by Graves) (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - General materials, 1980-2002 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Interviews – list of questions, undated, corrected proof, 1996, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Artifacts, 1957-1973, undated
    - Belt buckle, mailing box (Box 39, Folder 1)